const e="We could not find what you asked for, but got you this",i="insurance",o=200,t=120,a=[{id:36,question:"The professional service required for effective claims administration by insurers would be provided by",option:{a:"loss assessors",b:"risk managers",c:"loss adjusters",d:"claims consultants"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:196,question:"The following are the methods of claim settlement except",option:{a:"Cash",b:"Repair",c:"Reinstatement",d:"Repayment"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:289,question:"The division of total loss are",option:{a:"average loss and partial loss",b:"partial loss and full loss",c:"total loss and actual loss",d:"actual total loss and constructive total loss"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:345,question:"Which  of  the  following  functions  is  related  to  life assurance contract? Benefits are",option:{a:"determined  on  the  happening  of  insured  event",b:"determined by the indemnity doctrine",c:"determined at the inception of the policy",d:"assessed by the extent of the loss"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:81,question:"The following are examples of bad moral hazard except",option:{a:"Fraudulent activities",b:"Carelessness",c:"Honesty",d:"Unreasonableness"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:274,question:"A reinsurance contract in which the reassured agrees to offer and the reinsurer agrees to accept all risks of certain size within a defined class is",option:{a:"underwriting",b:"treaty",c:"tort",d:"syndicate"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:238,question:"Situation that are not included in the policy are usually referred to as",option:{a:"condition",b:"exception",c:"preamble",d:"operative clause"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:338,question:"The amount charged when a ship overstays at the port under a marine contract is",option:{a:"penalty",b:"fine",c:"overcharge",d:"demurrage"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:192,question:"The process of changing anything wrong with the policy to make it current is",option:{a:"Endorsement",b:"Specification",c:"Rectification",d:"Correction"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:1,question:"Which of the following policies will prevent loss of home if the wage earner dies?",option:{a:"Term assurance",b:"Endowment assurance",c:"Mortgage insurance",d:"Whole life assurance"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:326,question:"What is the full meaning of “NCRIB” in the insurance industry?",option:{a:"National  Council of  Registered Insurance  Brokers",b:"Nigerian  Council of  Registered Insurance  Brokers",c:"Nigerian Corporation of Registered Insurance Brokers",d:"National Corporation of Registered Insurance Brokers"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:201,question:"Insurance is defined as",option:{a:"risking of loss",b:"pooling of risk",c:"gathering of risk",d:"waiving of risk"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:48,question:"A <em>revival clause</em> in a life policy will allow an insured to revive a policy that lapsed on account of nonpayment of premium, provided the insured",option:{a:"can prove he is sick at the time",b:"cannot fall sick after the policy",c:"can prove he is in good health",d:"can recover from the ill health"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:51,question:"The primary function of insurance is",option:{a:"making profit",b:"managing of risk",c:"spreading of risk",d:"prevention of accident"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:145,question:"Factor that causes an exposure to injury, loss or damage is",option:{a:"Risk",b:"Hazard",c:"Peril",d:"Accident"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:224,question:"Risk that affect the society and whose causes are beyond human control is",option:{a:"particular risk",b:"pure risk",c:"fundamental risk",d:"static risk"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:105,question:"Which of the following is not a principle of insurance?",option:{a:"Indemnity",b:"Compensation",c:"Proximate cause",d:"Insurable interest"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:3,question:"An assurance policy taken by experts to cover possible negligence arising from their duties is",option:{a:"consequential loss",b:"professional indemnity",c:"cargo",d:"freight"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:264,question:"A reminder to the insured who may have forgotten to seek for continuation after his policy expiry date is",option:{a:"notification message",b:"renewal notice",c:"registration notice",d:"agreement notice"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:311,question:"Which  of  the  following  statements  is  true  about property insurance?",option:{a:"The probability that the event may occur",b:"The probability that the event will not occur",c:"The probability that the event may or may not occur",d:"The probability that the event must occur"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:10,question:"Which of the following is a contract of benefit?",option:{a:"Personal accident insurance",b:"Business interruption insurance",c:"Fire insurance",d:"Money insurance"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:61,question:"The payment made by the insured to the insurer upon which the validity of insurance is based is called",option:{a:"Exgratia payment",b:"Loss payment",c:"Compensation",d:"Premium"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:157,question:"------------ is used to bring amendment in a policy that is either to add in a new thing or removal of an existing thing in the policy",option:{a:"Excess",b:"Endorsement",c:"Claim form",d:"Policy"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:11,question:"Which of the following is not a feature of insurable interest?",option:{a:"Loss suffered",b:"subject matter",c:"Legal relationship",d:"Financial value"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:316,question:"Educational endowment policy is designed to protect the interest of",option:{a:"father",b:"mother",c:"child",d:"uncle"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:344,question:"Life  assurance  contract is useful to a policyholder in the area of",option:{a:"production",b:"protection",c:"industrialization",d:"rehabilitation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:200,question:"Another name for an insured in a life insurance contract is",option:{a:"Insurer",b:"Assured",c:"Assurer",d:"Agent"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:149,question:"The wrongful act willfully committed by either the master or the prejudice of either the owner or crew to the chatterer of the ship is",option:{a:"Barratry",b:"Caveat emptor",c:"Bailee",d:"Jettison"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:275,question:"A contract which has no legal effect is called",option:{a:"void policy",b:"voidable policy",c:"legal policy",d:"formal policy"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:137,question:"The sum paid for transporting the goods or for the hire of a ship is called",option:{a:"Marine cargo",b:"Freight insurance",c:"Hull insurance",d:"Risk insurance"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:257,question:"One of the following is legally used by the insured while the policy is being processed",option:{a:"indemnity form",b:"claim form",c:"cover note",d:"proposal form"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:72,question:"The risks which affect the society and whose causes are beyond human control is",option:{a:"particular risk",b:"static",c:"fundamental",d:"speculative"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:99,question:"A policy designed to protect individuals against negligence while carrying out their daily activities is called",option:{a:"business interruption",b:"employers liability",c:"engineering",d:"professional indemnity"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:87,question:"The principle of insurance which states that the insure should be truthful and disclose all material fact is",option:{a:"subrogation",b:"utmost good faith",c:"indemnity",d:"insurable interest"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:32,question:"A contract sold  by  insurance companies that  pay  a monthly or  quarterly income  benefit for the  life  of a person is",option:{a:"endowment",b:"annuity",c:"income",d:"freight"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:217,question:"Indemnity is not applicable in",option:{a:"assurance contract",b:"insurance contract",c:"insurance terms",d:"insurance content"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:281,question:"The process of examining, accepting or rejecting risks and classifying the ones accepted is",option:{a:"underwriting",b:"policy",c:"procedures",d:"warranty"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:343,question:"Which of the following activities is not involved in claims management?",option:{a:"Proof of loss",b:"Particulars of loss",c:"Premium calculation",d:"Primary investigation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:90,question:"Any circumstance that promotes the probability of a loss is called",option:{a:"accident",b:"hazard",c:"loss",d:"risk"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:130,question:"One of the following is the duty of the insured in insurance claim process",option:{a:"Late report of the loss",b:"Little idea of the loss size",c:"Quick report of the loss",d:"Hiding fact"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:60,question:"An individual who is interested in taking an insurance policy must fill a form of application called:",option:{a:"premium slip",b:"policy document",c:"proposal form",d:"claim form"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:268,question:"The payment made when the insured is not entitled to claim under a policy is",option:{a:"voluntary excess",b:"ex-gratia",c:"return premium",d:"premium"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:226,question:"Another name for utmost good faith",option:{a:"expirit - de - corps",b:"uberrimae fidei",c:"caveat emptor",d:"proximate cause"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:100,question:"Unlawful breaking and entering into any premises or place of safe keeping is covered under which of these policies?",option:{a:"burglary",b:"business interruption",c:"employers liability",d:"public liability"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:324,question:"Insurance is described as a risk",option:{a:"avoidance mechanism",b:"regulating mechanism",c:"transfer mechanism",d:"assessment mechanism"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:148,question:"The deliberate or intentional throwing over board of part of a cargo to lighten the ship in the interest of the reminder of the cargo is",option:{a:"Barratry",b:"Jettison",c:"Breach",d:"Caveat emptor"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:193,question:"A syndicate or an insurance company that transfer risk under re-insurance is",option:{a:"Cede",b:"Cession",c:"Commutation",d:"Cedant"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:68,question:"The buyer of insurance product is",option:{a:"Agent",b:"Broker",c:"Insured",d:"Insurer"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:285,question:"The principle of maritime law which makes owners of ship and cargo share in a lost incurred voluntarily is",option:{a:"general average",b:"special average",c:"specific average",d:"particular average"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:19,question:"A policy that combines cover for many perils as a single policy  to  suit  the  insurance  needs of  an insured is",option:{a:"accident policy",b:"protection policy",c:"paternal policy",d:"packaged policy"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:341,question:"The right of choice of option for method of indemnity is exercised by the",option:{a:"insured",b:"insurance broker",c:"insurance consultant",d:"insurer"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:331,question:"A motorist travelling from Ghana to Nigeria would be required to obtain one of the following types of motor insurance cover",option:{a:"green card",b:"brown card",c:"yellow card",d:"purple card"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:127,question:"Re-insurance contract is between",option:{a:"Re-insurer and insurer",b:"Re- insurance and insurance",c:"Co-insurer and insurer",d:"Insurance broker and re-insurer"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:12,question:"A prospective insured in an engineering insurance may be advised to purchase one of the following classes of insurance",option:{a:"fire cover",b:"boiler cover",c:"tempest cover",d:"equipment cover"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:80,question:"Hazard that relates to the subject matter of insurance is called",option:{a:"moral",b:"physical",c:"peril",d:"Good peril"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:279,question:"A policy that covers the peril of the sea is",option:{a:"aviation",b:"marine",c:"life",d:"fire"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:20,question:"A residential building built beside a petrol filling station is described as a",option:{a:"risk",b:"hazard",c:"peril",d:"liability"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:190,question:"When an   insurer agrees   to   replace   irreparably damaged or stolen goods with similar type it is called",option:{a:"Reinstatement",b:"Cash",c:"Repairs",d:"Replacement"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:45,question:"The consideration paid for insurance contract is",option:{a:"money",b:"commission",c:"premium",d:"fee"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:65,question:"The following are exempted from a contract because they do not have the contractual capacity except",option:{a:"Drunkard",b:"Alien",c:"Mental patient",d:"Adult"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:63,question:"The evidence of the contractual agreement between the insured and insurer is",option:{a:"policy",b:"proposal form",c:"insurance certificate",d:"cover note"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:103,question:"Below are insurable policies except",option:{a:"Earthquake",b:"Fire",c:"Life",d:"Marine"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:83,question:"The  principle  of  insurance  which  states  that a person must be in a legally recognized relationship to what is  insured  such  that  he  will  benefit  from its existence or suffer by its loss is",option:{a:"utmost good faith",b:"insurable interest",c:"proximate cause",d:"subrogation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:41,question:"A small fixed sum retained by the insured in the form of a claim is",option:{a:"slip",b:"severity",c:"excess",d:"frequency"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:215,question:"With insurance contract there is",option:{a:"certainty of occurrence",b:"uncertainty of occurrence",c:"certainty of reward",d:"uncertainty  of reward"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:42,question:"A voucher signed by the insured before collecting his claim is",option:{a:"money collect receipt",b:"discharge voucher",c:"payment receipt",d:"pay - in - slip"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:263,question:"Replacement of damaged property by the insurance company is",option:{a:"arbitration",b:"negotiation",c:"Re-instatement",d:"rectification"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:75,question:"The following risks are insurable except",option:{a:"particular",b:"pure",c:"static",d:"dynamic risk"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:247,question:"Third party provides cover only for damages to",option:{a:"assurer",b:"insurer",c:"2nd party",d:"another person"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:164,question:"Change for the transportation of goods by water is called",option:{a:"Bill",b:"Ticket",c:"Freight",d:"Consideration"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:235,question:"Proposal form is not applicable to the following except",option:{a:"aviation",b:"engineering",c:"large risk of fire",d:"fidelity guarantee"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:113,question:"A peril is best defined as",option:{a:"Chance of a loss",b:"The occurrence of a loan",c:"The cause of a loss",d:"The result of a loss"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:112,question:"Hazard that deals with the human habits and character that arises from human attitude and the conduct of people is called",option:{a:"physical",b:"Moral",c:"Static",d:"Dynamic"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:230,question:"one of these is a content of a proposal form",option:{a:"children of the proposer",b:"education of the proposer",c:"occupation of the proposer",d:"educational"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:147,question:"An insurance cover for lawyers, accountants and brokers is",option:{a:"Employment",b:"Professional",c:"Public",d:"Product"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:54,question:"The facts which might influence any party’s willingness to enter the contract or reject it is called",option:{a:"insurable fact",b:"insurance fact",c:"insured fact",d:"material fact"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:134,question:"A house worth N=60,000 insured against fire for N=40,000.  Fire destroyed and cause damage worth N=30,000. On the house under which insurance principle will the owner be entitled to compensation of N=30,000.",option:{a:"Contribution",b:"Subrogation",c:"indemnity",d:"Uberrimae fidei"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:125,question:"A card used by motorist in the West African sub-region is called",option:{a:"Brown card",b:"Certificate",c:"Insurance card",d:"visa card"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:78,question:"Factors which may influence the occurrence of a loss is",option:{a:"Risk",b:"Loss",c:"Peril",d:"Hazard"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:195,question:"Application by the insured to the insurer for the payment of money due under his contract of insurance is",option:{a:"Proof",b:"Evidence",c:"Claim",d:"Compensation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:161,question:"------------- is a policy designed to place the insured in the same financial position as he was immediately before the happening of the event insured against",option:{a:"Indemnity",b:"Subrogation",c:"Surrender value",d:"Actuary"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:135,question:"The person who calculate the amount given to the insured if he does not want to continue with the contract of insurance is called",option:{a:"Actuary",b:"Insurance agent",c:"Insurance broker",d:"Assessor loss adjuster"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:256,question:"Another name for the assured is",option:{a:"insurance company’s client",b:"insurance broker",c:"insurance company",d:"insurance agent"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:197,question:"Person who makes claim is called",option:{a:"Claimant",b:"Client",c:"Insured",d:"Insurer"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:298,question:"The cause of a loss is",option:{a:"peril",b:"hazard",c:"risk",d:"loss"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:34,question:"Renewal notice is  used by  insurers  to  remind the insured of the",option:{a:"reduction of cover",b:"continuation of cover",c:"expiration of cover",d:"increase of cover"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:212,question:"An insurance contract which does not involve mutuality of agreement in which only one of the parties involved in the contract makes promises that are legally binding is called",option:{a:"double contract",b:"single contract",c:"multilateral contract",d:"unilateral contract"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:260,question:"If the insured has been fully indemnified, the insurers are entitled to take any advantage due to the insured. Principle of insurance involved is",option:{a:"insurable interest",b:"contribution",c:"indemnity",d:"subrogation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:320,question:"A policy taken to cover several shipments for a sum assured is",option:{a:"floating policy",b:"valued policy",c:"declaration policy",d:"special policy"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:39,question:"The payment made when the insured is  not  entitled to claim under a policy is",option:{a:"voluntary excess",b:"ex-gratia",c:"return premium",d:"premium"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:16,question:"In the preparation of food for eat - in - customers, the cooks made a mistake in using excess quantity of an 	ingredient. A customer ate and  suffered  poisoning. 	Which policy of the operator would pick this liability?",option:{a:"Public liability",b:"Personal liability",c:"All risks insurance",d:"Loss of profit insurance"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:323,question:"A clause in marine insurance policy prohibiting the insured from giving up a damaged property is",option:{a:"deductible",b:"abandonment",c:"indemnity",d:"compensation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:50,question:"Which of the following is not a function of an insurance broker?",option:{a:"Assisting clients in paying premium",b:"Maintaining proper records of claims",c:"Assisting clients in connecting to insurers",d:"Assisting clients in effecting uninsured loss"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:239,question:"The part of a policy form that shows the name and address of the company is known as",option:{a:"heading",b:"conclusion",c:"condition",d:"preamble"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:28,question:"Family income option in a life policy provides that",option:{a:"the beneficiary will be paid for life",b:"the beneficiary receives the policy sum",c:"interest will be added monthly",d:"salary will be paid to the insured until death"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:185,question:"In insurance contract, failure to disclose all relevant material facts will render the contract",option:{a:"legal",b:"Voidable",c:"Void",d:"Implied"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:97,question:"A formal document containing the condition of the insurance contract is called",option:{a:"agreement",b:"contract form",c:"contract slip",d:"policy document"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:313,question:"Which class of life assurance would a young couple who desires to start a new business in five years time purchase?",option:{a:"Whole life policy",b:"Limited whole life policy",c:"Keyman policy",d:"Endowment policy"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:52,question:"An  insurance  feature  that  requires  the  parties  to disclose  all  material  facts  about  the  agreement is known as",option:{a:"Adhesion",b:"Disclosure",c:"Material fact",d:"Utmost good faith"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:166,question:"Another name for consequential loss is",option:{a:"Stop loss",b:"Credit insurance",c:"Business interruption insurance",d:"Excess loss"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:162,question:"The essential value of valid contract that states that the parties to a contract must be in perfect agreement and have a common mind is",option:{a:"Consideration",b:"Perpetual existence",c:"Excess",d:"Consensus ad-idem"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:294,question:"A risk that has its origin in the activities of an individual and the effects borne by this individual is called",option:{a:"pure risk",b:"particular risk",c:"speculative risk",d:"fundamental risk"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:29,question:"A provision in a policy that exempts an insurer from liability if the loss is less than a certain amount is",option:{a:"excess",b:"transfer",c:"lay days",d:"franchise"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:198,question:"A payment made by insurer as a form of sympathy to maintain goodwill is",option:{a:"Compensation payment",b:"Contract payment",c:"Charity payment",d:"Ex - gratia payment"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:267,question:"One of this is the consideration paid for insurance contract",option:{a:"fee",b:"cheque",c:"commission",d:"premium"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:191,question:"Cover note usually run for about",option:{a:"21 days",b:"one month",c:"12 months",d:"3 month"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:273,question:"A residential building built beside a petrol filling station is described as a",option:{a:"risk",b:"hazard",c:"peril",d:"liability"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:336,question:"The meaning of with <em>profit policy</em>  in life assurance is that the sum assured is paid",option:{a:"without profit",b:"with profit",c:"with interest",d:"without interest"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:315,question:"Which  of  the  following  would  not  give  cause  for subrogation right?",option:{a:"Benefit",b:"Contract",c:"Statute",d:"Salvage"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:33,question:"George effected two personal accident policies. The first policy provides N= 25,000.00 cover for loss of limb. The second policy provides N= 30,000.00 cover for loss of limb. What is the total amount that  George  will receive in the event of a valid loss of limb claim?",option:{a:"N= 5,000.00",b:"N= 25,000.00",c:"N= 30,000.00",d:"N= 55,000.00"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:295,question:"Business interruption insurance can also be called",option:{a:"consequential loss",b:"constructive loss",c:"partial  loss",d:"general loss"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:209,question:"In insurance, uncertainty of loss means",option:{a:"hazard",b:"risk",c:"accident",d:"earthquake"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:154,question:"---------- is the evidence cover of the risk given to the insured by the insurer",option:{a:"Cover",b:"Policy",c:"Claim",d:"Compensation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:181,question:"To break or act contrary to a law or promise means",option:{a:"Breach",b:"Shake",c:"Confirm",d:"Disagreement"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:262,question:"One of this is a method of claim settlement",option:{a:"price",b:"trade by barter",c:"exchange",d:"cash"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:333,question:"A  trade  group for insurance  companies in  Nigeria is called",option:{a:"Chartered Insurance Institute of Nigeria",b:"National Insurance Commission",c:"Nigerian Corporation of Registered Insurance Brokers",d:"Nigerian Insurers Association"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:329,question:"The  sum  insured  for  a  risk  is  N= 150,000  and  was accepted  for  fire  insurance at a rate of  0.25%. How much will the insured pay as a premium?",option:{a:"N= 125",b:"N= 375",c:"N= 500",d:"N= 875"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:216,question:"With assurance contract there is",option:{a:"uncertainly of reward",b:"certainty of reward",c:"certainty of occurrence",d:"uncertainty of occurrence"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:249,question:"The deliberate throwing overboard of part of a cargo to lighten the ship is called",option:{a:"barratry",b:"overthrown",c:"voyaging",d:"jettisoning"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:290,question:"Marine insurance policy which covers all the ship or vessels belonging to one owner is",option:{a:"flect policy",b:"mixed policy",c:"value policy",d:"fixed policy"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"}],n={message:e,subject:i,status:200,total:120,data:a};export{a as data,n as default,e as message,o as status,i as subject,t as total};
